<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-05T00:49:40-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dhonni Meye</title><subtitle>My musings and mumblings as I travel, cook and navigate the journey of life.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My YouTube - How it all began 🎬</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/my-youtube" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My YouTube - How it all began 🎬" /><published>2018-12-31T11:50:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-31T11:50:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/youtube</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/my-youtube">&lt;p&gt;My first vlogging experience was when I went on a solo trip to Pondicherry on September 2016. I tried to capture clips at the beach with my voice in the background. I never shared those clips. I don’t think I have those with me anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jump 1 year to July 2017. I decided to move to Seattle, Washington, United States with my husband. This was my first international travel and I decided to capture the entire experience as a video log. I did click a couple of clips but never ended up compiling them. I do have those clips with me. I should make a video. That’s for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, August 2017. It had been around 1 month that I had moved to Seattle. I was waiting for my EAD (work permit) and hence spending most of my time at home. Vlogger streak strikes back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created my first video when we got a tent for our camping trip. I used iMovie to edit it. I posted it on Instagram. Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BYK6bueDYeN/?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This was the first video I ever edited and I believe I did a good job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take this seriously and created my YouTube channel - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Priyanka Vlogs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; which I later changed to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dhonni Meye&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Check out my YouTube channel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC1txbrDxS1EpyQLHGI7EAzA&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Please subscribe to my channel if you enjoy my videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first video on YouTube was about a friend’s wedding. You will not see since I had to remove it for my friend’s personal reasons. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC1txbrDxS1EpyQLHGI7EAzA/videos&quot;&gt;Here are the rest&lt;/a&gt;. I started as a personal vlog, travel and cooking channel. But I like to explore and I upload other content like comedy, lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So well.. that’s how it all began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you enjoy my story? Let me know in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,
Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My first vlogging experience was when I went on a solo trip to Pondicherry on September 2016. I tried to capture clips at the beach with my voice in the background. I never shared those clips. I don’t think I have those with me anymore.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/my-youtube.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Travel Packing &amp;amp; Me 🎒</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel-checklist" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Travel Packing &amp; Me 🎒" /><published>2018-12-31T02:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-31T02:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel-checklist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel-checklist">&lt;p&gt;I love to travel, but my biggest concern with travelling used to be &lt;strong&gt;packing&lt;/strong&gt;. The thoughts of &lt;em&gt;What if I forget this? What if I need that?&lt;/em&gt; made me crazy. Over time, I have come to a realization - &lt;strong&gt;money&lt;/strong&gt;(preferably in the form of card), &lt;strong&gt;passport&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;phone&lt;/strong&gt; are the &lt;strong&gt;MUST HAVES&lt;/strong&gt; during a trip. Rest, you can &lt;em&gt;beg, borrow or steal&lt;/em&gt;! Just kidding, what did you take the money for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I travel light. I don’t remember the last time I had a carry on. Leave alone a checked bag. &lt;strong&gt;Backpack&lt;/strong&gt; - my ultimate friend. I only carry essentials. You will find below, the packing checklist I follow. Carrying some items like umbrella, swimwear, jacket depend on the location and weather conditions. Otherwise, this is it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debit / Credit card + Cash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Valid ID / Passport &amp;amp; visa docs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Electronics
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Phone + Charger&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Earphones&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Power bank + Charger&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tablet&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Camera + Charger&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Laptop + Charger&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medicines
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fever&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Anti diarrheal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Headache&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Muscle cramp&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Acidity&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Band aid&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mint&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clothes &amp;amp; accessories
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Underwear&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sleepwear&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Swimwear&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tops&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jacket&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scarf&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Socks&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Slippers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Spare spectacles&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Contact lenses&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sunglasses&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Umbrella&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toiletries(100 ml or less)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hand sanitizer&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Toothbrush + Toothpaste&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lip balm&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Red lipstick&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cream&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sunscreen&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Comb + Hair ties&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Safety pins&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Face wipes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Feminine hygiene products&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snacks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extra foldable bags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backpack I use - https://amzn.to/2BVHLEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think my list is too long? What are the things that you can’t travel without? Do let me know in the comment section below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,
Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I love to travel, but my biggest concern with travelling used to be packing. The thoughts of What if I forget this? What if I need that? made me crazy. Over time, I have come to a realization - money(preferably in the form of card), passport and phone are the MUST HAVES during a trip. Rest, you can beg, borrow or steal! Just kidding, what did you take the money for?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/packing-checklist.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello 🌻</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello 🌻" /><published>2018-12-30T14:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-30T14:48:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello">&lt;p&gt;Hi there! Glad that you found me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Priyanka. I am software developer by profession living in Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love exploring new places, trying out new cuisines and creating posts on my experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to know you. Let me know your thoughts on this website in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,
Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hi there! Glad that you found me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/hello.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A few things to keep in mind before your next trip to Cancun, Mexico</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cancun-trip" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A few things to keep in mind before your next trip to Cancun, Mexico" /><published>2018-01-05T00:42:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-05T00:42:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cancun-trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cancun-trip">&lt;p&gt;We spent an amazing Christmas vacation at Cancun, Mexico. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/UrmSwPDCucI&quot;&gt;Here is a short clip of our trip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/UrmSwPDCucI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoyed it? Awesome!! Let’s go ahead and talk about a few things we did right and a few things we wish we had known before our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mexicans speak Spanish. Learn a few Spanish words. The announcement for our flight in Seattle was in Spanish, Customs Officer in point of entry at Mexico spoke to us in Spanish, all airport members in Mexico spoke Spanish. You’ll feel comfortable if you follow some of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not lose the tourist card provided to you at the port of entry in Mexico. You will need it while exiting Mexico. I almost dumped mine, but luckily found it in my bag pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not driving to and from the airport, do not rent a cab from the airport. Either call your hotel for a pickup service or pre-book shuttles. We used &lt;a href=&quot;https://happyshuttlecancun.com/&quot;&gt;Happy Shuttle&lt;/a&gt;. It is the most efficient means of transporation for a trip to/from the airport. Cost 12 USD per person. The driver was friendly and the ride was comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are paying by cash, use Mexican Pesos. Most shops accept US Dollars. But the exchange rate is poor. We were paying in dollars first and we lost a fair bit in the exchange. A cab ride that costs 450 Mexican Pesos(23 USD according to current exchange rate) cost us 30 USD. Later, we exchanged dollars at our hotel and we got a decent rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend a few extra bucks and get access to unlimited food, drinks, free room-service and some hotel coupons by staying in an all-inclusive hotel on the beach. Before booking the hotel, check the number of restaurants it has. The more, the merrier. We stayed at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.secretsresorts.com/en_us/resorts/mexico/vine-cancun.html&quot;&gt;Secrets the Vine, Cancun&lt;/a&gt;. It had 6 restuarants and 3 bars. The staff was very friendly and service was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it is an all-inclusive resort, tips are not included. Although it is not mandatory, tip the room service lady,the server, the bartender, the bellboy. Tipping a dollar for a drink or two, a dollar after a meal is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your day trips to Chichen Itza or Tulum, you will find good deals on websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com&quot;&gt;TripAdvisor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedia.com/&quot;&gt;Expedia&lt;/a&gt;. Avoid booking it from the hotel concierge as they are generally more expensive. We booked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com/AttractionProductReview-g150805-d12005530-Full_Day_Guided_Tour_of_Chichen_Itza_Mayan_Archaeological_Site_and_Cenote_Swimming.html&quot;&gt;Day trip to Chichen Itza&lt;/a&gt; for 49 USD per person. The hotel was charging 117 USD per person for the same trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tourists have a concern about travelling to Mexico. However, Cancun felt very safe. You can always check &lt;a href=&quot;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/traveladvisories/mexico-travel-advisory.html&quot;&gt;Mexico travel advisory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you find these tips useful? Do you have any tips that you would like to share? Let me know in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,
Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We spent an amazing Christmas vacation at Cancun, Mexico. Here is a short clip of our trip.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/cancun.jpg" /></entry></feed>