<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-08T13:24:29-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dhonni Meye</title><subtitle>My musings and mumblings as I travel, cook and navigate the journey of life.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Homemade Nutella | Palm oil free | Dairy free | Vegan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/homemade-nutella_vegan-vegetarian-dairy-free" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homemade Nutella | Palm oil free | Dairy free | Vegan" /><published>2019-02-08T12:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-08T12:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/homemade-nutella</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/homemade-nutella_vegan-vegetarian-dairy-free">&lt;p&gt;Did you know that 100 grams of  palm oil consists of 45 grams of saturated fats whereas 100g grams of hazelnuts consists of only 4.5 grams of saturated fats? Why do you need to know this? Well, look at the picture below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/store-bought-nutella.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Store bought nutells&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the palm oil, hazelnuts ratio in the world’s most popular hazelnut spread. Concerning, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But who doesn’t love Nutella? It is sooooo yummy! Solution? Let’s make it. Our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here goes the recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients--&quot;&gt;Ingredients -&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raw hazelnuts - 250 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coconut oil(or any vegetable oil) - 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sweetened cocoa powder - 60 grams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaggery sugar(or coconut sugar) - 5 1tablespoons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt - 1 pinch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vanilla essence - 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;steps--&quot;&gt;Steps -&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread raw hazelnuts in a single layer on a baking sheet and toast for 12 minutes(or until skin is brown) at 350F. Alterbatively, you can toast it on medium flame in a flat pan. Let it cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hazelnuts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Toast hazelnuts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hazelnut shells do not taste good, so remove them. An easy way to do so is shown below. Half-fill a container and shake vigorously. The shells come off easily. Alternatively, you can place the nuts in a dry cloth and rubs off the skins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hazelnuts-remove-shell.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Remove hazelnut shells&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grind the hazelnuts in a food processor at full speed until you get a nut butter like consistency. This should take around 5 minutes in a heavy duty food processor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hazelnuts-grind.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grind hazelnuts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add all the other ingredients to the food processor - oil, cocoa powder, sugar, salt, vanilla essence. You can adjust the sugar according to your preference.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Grind until you get a smooth and shiny consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nutella-mix.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grind ingredients&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store in a jar, let it cool and wohoo!! Homemade nutella is ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/homemade-nutella.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grind ingredients&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy it with crepes, fruits or all by itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;taste-test---the-truth&quot;&gt;Taste-test - the truth&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This nutella does not taste exactly like a store bought Nutella, but it surely tastes great! The most important fact is that it contains no palm oil, no dairy and no preservatives.  If you do not want it dairy free, you can add melted milk chocolate. I haven’t tried it, but I guess it is going to taste more authentic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do try this out and let me know how you like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,
Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Did you know that 100 grams of palm oil consists of 45 grams of saturated fats whereas 100g grams of hazelnuts consists of only 4.5 grams of saturated fats? Why do you need to know this? Well, look at the picture below.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/nutella.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Weekend in Houston</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/houston-trip" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weekend in Houston" /><published>2019-02-03T15:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-03T15:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/houston-trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/houston-trip"></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/houston.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I completed the Whole30 challenge and I feel great 💁</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/whole30-experience" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I completed the Whole30 challenge and I feel great 💁" /><published>2019-02-03T14:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-03T14:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/whole-30-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/whole30-experience">&lt;p&gt;Hey guys!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first day of 2019, I shared a video on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC1txbrDxS1EpyQLHGI7EAzA&quot;&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; that I will be taking up and completing the Whole30 challenge. If you would like to watch it, you can check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6wrYi0xA2ZE&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6wrYi0xA2ZE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And guess what, I have successfully completed it. &lt;strong&gt;Yayy!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resolution 1 of 2019 - ✅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not go through the reintroduction phase, which is mainly to observe what food categories suit your body and what don’t. I have reintroduced some food items in small amounts already and I am doing fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how did it go? Continue reading to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-observations--&quot;&gt;My observations -&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people observe huge changes in their energy levels, sleep, mood, skin, digestion. I didn’t notice any significant change in those areas but I did see &lt;em&gt;consistent energy levels&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;em&gt;food habits&lt;/em&gt; have really &lt;em&gt;improved&lt;/em&gt;. Since I did not have a lot of snacking options, and I almost do not drink coffee, I &lt;em&gt;drank a lot of water&lt;/em&gt; (around 3 liters every day) and it felt good. I made sure I am eating a &lt;em&gt;filling breakfast&lt;/em&gt;. I was watching what and how much I eat (never happened before). I have almost given up unmindful munching. While on this challenge I &lt;em&gt;never felt greasy or bloated&lt;/em&gt; (I felt this very frequently before this challenge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although weight-loss is not a motive of this challenge, it is worth mentioning that I did &lt;em&gt;lose a couple of kilos&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-sample-of-what-i-ate-in-a-day--&quot;&gt;A sample of ‘What I ate in a day’ -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/whole30-breakfast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Breakfast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Breakfast&lt;/em&gt; - 2 eggs fried in a pinch of coconut oil and 1 chicken sausage and a small cup of 	orange juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snack&lt;/em&gt; - Banana sprinkled with cinnamon powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lunch&lt;/em&gt; - Roasted chicken slices with lettuce, fajitas, tomato, onions, lime juice and cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snack&lt;/em&gt; - 3 almonds and 3 cashews and some plantain chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/whole30-chicken.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tandoori chicken.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dinner&lt;/em&gt; - Home made tandoori chicken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-deal-with-snack-and-sugar-cravings&quot;&gt;How to deal with snack and sugar cravings?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of Whole30 compliant snack options out there. Some of my favorites are -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apple and almond butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Banana with cinnamon powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Berries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dried mango slices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date and coconut balls with pistachios&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guacamole&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plantain chips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cucumber with salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Almonds and cashews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Almond milk with banana
While snacking, just keep in mind to keep a watch how much you are eating. The best way to do it is to not eat from the source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-went-as-planned&quot;&gt;What went as planned?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eating fruit as a snack&lt;/em&gt; - Fruits saved me from failing in this challenge. I ate fruits with 	almost every meal of the day. They kept me full and also helped me shoo away my sugar 			cravings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eating Indian meals&lt;/em&gt; - I love Indian food and I can eat it forever. I did not try too hard to 	 follow and cook Whole30 special recipes. I cooked Indian meals and I thoroughly enjoyed it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keeping an eye on what I am eating&lt;/em&gt; - I took a quick look at the ingredients list on the 		packaging while at the grocery store. If at a restaurant, I went through the ingredients in 	the menu or asked the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-did-not-go-as-expected&quot;&gt;What did not go as expected?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Planning ahead and meal prepping&lt;/em&gt; - I sucked at it. I did it for the initial 3-4 days and then 	 it did not happen at all. I went with the flow and ate whatever I cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eating outside&lt;/em&gt; - I did not manage to save food from previous night’s dinner for lunch 			everyday. I ended up with no choice but to eat outside. Most lunch options in my office 		cafeteria or in the nearby lunch place are not Whole30 complaint. So I either ended up eating 	  fruits or sometimes I had to skip lunch (which is not recommended).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;takeaways&quot;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;This challenge is not as hard as it sounds&lt;/em&gt; - You can do it. Try it for 15 days if you find 30 days too daunting for your first attempt.
  -* You can travel and still follow your eating rules* - We travelled to Houston, Texas on the 25th 	day of this challenge. I love barbecues and Texas is famous for them. I controlled my 	cravings (I did try a teeny-tiny bit of the bbq rib but that’s it) and continued to eat as per 	Whole30 food rules.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are in more control of our cravings than we think&lt;/em&gt; - I am a &lt;em&gt;bigggg&lt;/em&gt; sugar lover. I had strong 	   cravings during the first week. I walked along the dessert counters in WholeFoods telling the 	 cherry pies that I miss them. Eventually, I got over it. If someone at work got a huge box 	of donuts, I was able to say no without feeling sad about it. This holds for things like 		eating 2 servings of pulao and chicken because it is so yummy. Keep it for tomorrow. You will 	  get the chance to relish it once again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Only the first bite matters&lt;/em&gt; - The crazy sugar cravings can be satisfied with one bite of a 		cheesecake. You do not need to eat the whole slice at one go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your body will thank you for eating mindfully&lt;/em&gt; - It feels great to wake up in the morning with 	  your stomach not feeling full from last night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;will-i-do-it-again&quot;&gt;Will I do it again?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;. I might not do it for 30 days at once, but I will surely do it for 15 days. It is a very easy way to cleanse your system, eat mindfully and feel great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you tried the Whole30 challenge? Do you think you will try it? Let me know your comments below. Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey guys!!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/whole30-experience.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My YouTube - How it all began 🎬</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/my-youtube" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My YouTube - How it all began 🎬" /><published>2018-12-31T11:50:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-31T11:50:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/youtube</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/my-youtube">&lt;p&gt;My first vlogging experience was when I went on a solo trip to Pondicherry on September 2016. I tried to capture clips at the beach with my voice in the background. I never shared those clips. I don’t think I have those with me anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jump 1 year to July 2017. I decided to move to Seattle, Washington, United States with my husband. This was my first international travel and I decided to capture the entire experience as a video log. I did click a couple of clips but never ended up compiling them. I do have those clips with me. I should make a video. That’s for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, August 2017. It had been around 1 month that I had moved to Seattle. I was waiting for my EAD (work permit) and hence spending most of my time at home. Vlogger streak strikes back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created my first video when we got a tent for our camping trip. I used iMovie to edit it. I posted it on Instagram. Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BYK6bueDYeN/?utm_source=ig_web_button_share_sheet&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This was the first video I ever edited and I believe I did a good job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take this seriously and created my YouTube channel - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Priyanka Vlogs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; which I later changed to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dhonni Meye&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Check out my YouTube channel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC1txbrDxS1EpyQLHGI7EAzA&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Please subscribe to my channel if you enjoy my videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first video on YouTube was about a friend’s wedding. You will not see since I had to remove it for my friend’s personal reasons. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC1txbrDxS1EpyQLHGI7EAzA/videos&quot;&gt;Here are the rest&lt;/a&gt;. I started as a personal vlog, travel and cooking channel. But I like to explore and I upload other content like comedy, lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So well.. that’s how it all began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you enjoy my story? Let me know in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,
Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My first vlogging experience was when I went on a solo trip to Pondicherry on September 2016. I tried to capture clips at the beach with my voice in the background. I never shared those clips. I don’t think I have those with me anymore.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/my-youtube.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Travel Packing &amp;amp; Me 🎒</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel-checklist" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Travel Packing &amp; Me 🎒" /><published>2018-12-31T02:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-31T02:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel-checklist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel-checklist">&lt;p&gt;I love to travel, but my biggest concern with travelling used to be &lt;strong&gt;packing&lt;/strong&gt;. The thoughts of &lt;em&gt;What if I forget this? What if I need that?&lt;/em&gt; made me crazy. Over time, I have come to a realization - &lt;strong&gt;money&lt;/strong&gt;(preferably in the form of card), &lt;strong&gt;passport&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;phone&lt;/strong&gt; are the &lt;strong&gt;MUST HAVES&lt;/strong&gt; during a trip. Rest, you can &lt;em&gt;beg, borrow or steal&lt;/em&gt;! Just kidding, what did you take the money for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I travel light. I don’t remember the last time I had a carry on. Leave alone a checked bag. &lt;strong&gt;Backpack&lt;/strong&gt; - my ultimate friend. I only carry essentials. You will find below, the packing checklist I follow. Carrying some items like umbrella, swimwear, jacket depend on the location and weather conditions. Otherwise, this is it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Debit / Credit card + Cash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Valid ID / Passport &amp;amp; visa docs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Electronics
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Phone + Charger&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Earphones&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Power bank + Charger&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tablet&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Camera + Charger&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Laptop + Charger&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medicines
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fever&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Anti diarrheal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Headache&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Muscle cramp&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Acidity&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Band aid&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mint&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clothes &amp;amp; accessories
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Underwear&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sleepwear&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Swimwear&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tops&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jacket&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scarf&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Socks&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Slippers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Spare spectacles&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Contact lenses&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sunglasses&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Umbrella&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toiletries(100 ml or less)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hand sanitizer&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Toothbrush + Toothpaste&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lip balm&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Red lipstick&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cream&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sunscreen&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Comb + Hair ties&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Safety pins&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Face wipes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Feminine hygiene products&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snacks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extra foldable bags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backpack I use - https://amzn.to/2BVHLEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think my list is too long? What are the things that you can’t travel without? Do let me know in the comment section below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,
Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I love to travel, but my biggest concern with travelling used to be packing. The thoughts of What if I forget this? What if I need that? made me crazy. Over time, I have come to a realization - money(preferably in the form of card), passport and phone are the MUST HAVES during a trip. Rest, you can beg, borrow or steal! Just kidding, what did you take the money for?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/packing-checklist.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello 🌻</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello 🌻" /><published>2018-12-30T14:48:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-30T14:48:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello">&lt;p&gt;Hi there! Glad that you found me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Priyanka. I am software developer by profession living in Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love exploring new places, trying out new cuisines and creating posts on my experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to know you. Let me know your thoughts on this website in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,
Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hi there! Glad that you found me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/hello.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A few things to keep in mind before your next trip to Cancun, Mexico</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cancun-trip" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A few things to keep in mind before your next trip to Cancun, Mexico" /><published>2018-01-05T00:42:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-05T00:42:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cancun-trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cancun-trip">&lt;p&gt;We spent an amazing Christmas vacation at Cancun, Mexico. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/UrmSwPDCucI&quot;&gt;Here is a short clip of our trip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; src=&quot;https://youtube.com/embed/UrmSwPDCucI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoyed it? Awesome!! Let’s go ahead and talk about a few things we did right and a few things we wish we had known before our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mexicans speak Spanish. Learn a few Spanish words. The announcement for our flight in Seattle was in Spanish, Customs Officer in point of entry at Mexico spoke to us in Spanish, all airport members in Mexico spoke Spanish. You’ll feel comfortable if you follow some of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not lose the tourist card provided to you at the port of entry in Mexico. You will need it while exiting Mexico. I almost dumped mine, but luckily found it in my bag pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not driving to and from the airport, do not rent a cab from the airport. Either call your hotel for a pickup service or pre-book shuttles. We used &lt;a href=&quot;https://happyshuttlecancun.com/&quot;&gt;Happy Shuttle&lt;/a&gt;. It is the most efficient means of transporation for a trip to/from the airport. Cost 12 USD per person. The driver was friendly and the ride was comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are paying by cash, use Mexican Pesos. Most shops accept US Dollars. But the exchange rate is poor. We were paying in dollars first and we lost a fair bit in the exchange. A cab ride that costs 450 Mexican Pesos(23 USD according to current exchange rate) cost us 30 USD. Later, we exchanged dollars at our hotel and we got a decent rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend a few extra bucks and get access to unlimited food, drinks, free room-service and some hotel coupons by staying in an all-inclusive hotel on the beach. Before booking the hotel, check the number of restaurants it has. The more, the merrier. We stayed at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.secretsresorts.com/en_us/resorts/mexico/vine-cancun.html&quot;&gt;Secrets the Vine, Cancun&lt;/a&gt;. It had 6 restuarants and 3 bars. The staff was very friendly and service was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it is an all-inclusive resort, tips are not included. Although it is not mandatory, tip the room service lady,the server, the bartender, the bellboy. Tipping a dollar for a drink or two, a dollar after a meal is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your day trips to Chichen Itza or Tulum, you will find good deals on websites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com&quot;&gt;TripAdvisor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedia.com/&quot;&gt;Expedia&lt;/a&gt;. Avoid booking it from the hotel concierge as they are generally more expensive. We booked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com/AttractionProductReview-g150805-d12005530-Full_Day_Guided_Tour_of_Chichen_Itza_Mayan_Archaeological_Site_and_Cenote_Swimming.html&quot;&gt;Day trip to Chichen Itza&lt;/a&gt; for 49 USD per person. The hotel was charging 117 USD per person for the same trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tourists have a concern about travelling to Mexico. However, Cancun felt very safe. You can always check &lt;a href=&quot;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/traveladvisories/traveladvisories/mexico-travel-advisory.html&quot;&gt;Mexico travel advisory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you find these tips useful? Do you have any tips that you would like to share? Let me know in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,
Priyanka&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We spent an amazing Christmas vacation at Cancun, Mexico. Here is a short clip of our trip.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/cancun.jpg" /></entry></feed>